-[rapid hoofbeats]
-[cart wheels rattling]
♪
[CAPTAIN] Are you sure, sir?
This is far enough?
[DENKEN] It will do.
I can make it
the rest of the way by myself.
This is where
our journey must end,
for my journey
continues on foot.
If you're certain,
travel safe, sir.
-[hoofbeats]
-[cart wheels rattling]
♪
[♪ opening theme song playing]
It's in ruins.
Well, it takes time to rebuild
after a dragon attack.
I didn't realize
you guys had to deal
with dragons up here.
The Plateau's fun never ends.
It could be much worse,
-you know.
-How.
[FRIEREN] When I traveled
with Himmel and the others,
we were attacked
by a thunder of dragons.
Can you even imagine
that many in one place?
I'd rather not.
Uh, just to clarify,
do they not usually move
as a thunder?
Was this village attacked
by a thunder?
[MAYOR] Yes.
Seems the beasts have made
a nearby forest their home.
You three are our best shot
at defeating them.
"Normal" around here
isn't very normal.
Not normal at all.
[men grunting]
Your village is
past the point of saving.
You should rebuild
somewhere new.
How could we?
As dangerous as it is,
this is our home.
-[MAN 1] Incoming.
-[MAN 2] Let me help.
[MAN 3] Need more hands?
[FERN]
He's right, Mistress Frieren.
That was a cruel thing to say.
[STARK] Somebody's gotta
help these villagers.
One dragon
is a challenge enough.
To face a horde...
We will not come out unscathed.
We protect other people's homes,
don't we?
It shall depend on the reward.
Alas, our village
is extremely poor.
I fear we have
nothing to pay you with.
You don't have
a single grimoire?
There's one,
but it's terribly useless
and I doubt
it's of any interest to you.
It allows you to say
tongue twisters
without tripping
over your words.
[FERN] Goodness, that does sound
terribly useless.
At the end of the day,
a spell is still a spell.
You mentioned
they live in a nearby wood?
Yes, they're somewhere
in that forest up ahead.
If we can pick up
even a trace of mana,
we can track them down.
♪
[FRIEREN]
Looks like we continue straight.
I'm impressed
by your magic all the time.
But when it's
so applicable like this,
I'm reminded how amazing it is.
Do you have
any more praise for me?
You can't give in.
No more careless praise.
It's bad for Mistress Frieren's
development.
[STARK]
Hm... I guess that's true.
[FRIEREN] What exactly
do you two take me for?
If anyone still cares,
the dragons are this way.
♪
-[FRIEREN] There they are.
-[dragons snoring softly]
[STARK]
That's a lot of dragons.
[FRIEREN]
But luckily they're small.
They won't be nearly as strong
as that solar dragon.
Regardless of size,
dragons are smart.
Don't let them surround you.
I say we draw them
to a single point
and take them down at once.
Well, Stark?
Think that you're up
for the job?
You're an experienced
dragon fighter these days.
Tall order.
More like experienced bait.
[dragon growls]
Shall we begin?
You better actually fire
some spells this time!
♪
If you slay them all first,
I won't have to.
[Stark grunts]
[dragons growling]
[Stark grunting]
[Stark gasps]
[dragon growling]
♪
[Stark grunting]
[Stark grunts]
[Stark groans]
That job
was ridiculously intense.
At least the village's church
wasn't destroyed.
Mr. Stark, I watched
an angry dragon
-chew on your head.
-[dragon grunting]
[FERN] How are you
not in worse shape?
[STARK] Uh...
I got no clue.
Eisen's head
was often chewed as well.
Durable skulls must be
a normal warrior trait.
Mistress, nothing about
Mister Eisen is normal.
[MAYOR] It took some rummaging.
But here's
the promised grimoire.
Thank you
for protecting our village.
I've noticed an odd tendency.
Whenever we help someone out,
you almost always
blindly demand payment.
Because Himmel the Hero
did the same.
That's surprising.
Agreed. I imagined him
as the sort that would want
to help others for free.
Curious, huh?
Used to confound me, too.
Thank you so much
for your help, sir.
[WOMAN] I only wish
that there was some way
for us to properly repay you.
But as you can see,
our village is poor.
Though we can't offer much,
I do hope you'll take this.
[EISEN]
I won't allow it, Himmel.
We cannot accept their food.
Is that a grimoire?
[MAN] Uh, unfortunately not.
It's a notebook we received
from a traveling merchant
some time ago.
We have no use for it.
♪
[scribbling]
[FRIEREN]
I have a question, Himmel.
Why demand payment
in exchange for our aid,
when you don't care
what we receive?
If they pay us,
they don't owe us anything.
No favors and no praise.
After all, we are
the party of heroes.
We're meant to be
protectors of the people,
not collectors
of gratitude and debt.
We should give, not take.
♪
If the people we help
are indebted to us,
then the only people that we're
truly serving are ourselves.
You see?
That's why even
the most ridiculous spells
suffice as payment in my eyes.
Noble.
[FRIEREN] Now start thinking
of a good tongue twister.
[FERN] I still think
you just want more grimoires.
[STARK] Next time,
maybe you can ask for one
that prevents dragons
from biting your head.
♪
[EISEN]
What's your analysis, Frieren?
Is it letting up?
[FRIEREN] It still looks like
we won't be able
to head out for a while.
[EISEN]
That's some terrible luck.
I can't believe
we're stuck here.
I'm so bored, I could die.
Blame the bottle ache,
not the boredom.
[Himmel chuckles]
♪
Keep your spirits high,
my brave friends!
We're on
a life-changing adventure
to slay the Demon King.
[EISEN] Yet we haven't been
able to adventure for days now.
Adventures are about
more than fighting
and wandering pebbled roads.
Sometimes, an adventure
can be enduring
a series
of dreadful days indoors.
[EISEN] Dreadful is your word,
not ours.
[Himmel gasps]
[EISEN] What are you
thrashing about for?
Has death come
to catch you, too?
[HIMMEL] Uh...
[thunder rumbling]
[HIMMEL] It's nothing.
We've been waiting
around this city for a week
and the weather still
hasn't gotten better.
Will you be able
to ferry us across today?
You must know the answer.
Though made of wood,
my boat is not a coffin.
I suppose not.
I've heard of storms
over oceans,
but I didn't know
they can form over lakes, too.
Lake Korridor
is the largest body of water
in all the northern lands.
It's larger than
some inland seas.
[STARK] I believe it.
You can hardly make out
the far shore.
Immense mountain ranges
to both the east and the west
disrupt air currents,
making this time of year
brutally stormy.
It's not uncommon
for large, established ships
to sink in this season.
[FERN]
And because of the wind,
there's no chance we can cross
with flying magic.
[FRIEREN]
It would be difficult to fly
to the other side
on a clear day.
The distance to shore
is vaster than you think.
[FRIEREN]
I might be able to make it.
But skilled as you are,
you lack the mana.
Perhaps we would be better off
venturing around the lake.
[FRIEREN] We most certainly
would not be.
Wait, why?
I told you about the mountains
to the east and the west.
[muffled] Mmm.
They're as mighty as the lake.
Trying to barrel
our way through
without so much
as a mountain pass
to hang our hats on...
[muffled] Mmm.
...would be suicide.
We should stay put and wait
for a few months.
It'll be leagues safer
and timelier
than challenging the elements
head on with no plan.
Fortunately, this is
a fairly large port city
and trading hub.
It's the perfect place
to pass the time.
♪
[STARK] One winter later
and here we are.
Can you take us?
Yes.
But only if you're able to pay.
Even though
the storms have passed,
this voyage is not a safe one.
The risk will need to be
worth it.
That's almost offensive.
We'd have the funds if someone
hadn't bought so many grimoires.
Boredom took control.
Fine. If you can't pay,
we'll exchange favors.
On an island just offshore,
there's an abandoned monastery.
It's protected by a barrier.
According to legend,
if you can get through,
you'll find the memoirs
of Himmel the Hero.
In my grandfather's time,
Himmel the Hero saved our city
and its people.
I've looked up to him
ever since I was a child.
We've been starving
for those memoirs for ages.
I'd like you
to find them for me.
Himmel's memoirs, huh?
Poor Himmel.
All that work to record
your travels
just for the pages to slip away.
Must have been
very disappointing.
I can't believe they've been
hiding there this whole while.
Sure.
You've got yourself
a favor.
♪
It feels like
we're on the ocean.
Is that a whole fleet of ships?
Indeed.
If you want to move people
or goods north,
now is the best time to do it.
And the recent rumors
are playing a role.
They say there's a Golden Land
where things from streets
to rooftops
are made of pure gold.
More people are interested
in crossing the lake
than normal.
A Golden Land?
You think it really exists?
[sailor chuckles] Who can say?
All I know is
I've never met anyone
who's actually been there.
Probably just another tall tale.
[SAILOR] There's the island.
I was expecting the barrier
to be much stronger.
In its defense,
it must be several decades old.
I bet this monastery was nice.
Why would anybody abandon it?
A monster attacked
and the old roof couldn't
weather the damage.
This place has been around
for a long while.
That makes sense.
And explains why they erected
the barrier in a hurry.
Mm, and why was that?
Monasteries are known
to house books.
Especially ones that are old,
valuable, and irreplaceable.
[STARK] So, uh...
[FERN]
So they put up the barrier
to protect the books
they couldn't take with them.
That should do it.
Now, let's see what we can find.
[FERN]
What happened to the monks?
Where did they go?
[SAILOR] Who knows?
It was abandoned ages ago.
The only knowledge that remains
about this place
is the legend
of Himmel the Hero's memoirs.
[footsteps]
[door creaks open]
[STARK] This library is massive.
[FERN] There's a statue
of Mr. Himmel.
He nailed the pose
for that one.
[Fern gasps softly]
♪
[FRIEREN] Hello, book.
Is it you?
♪
Yes.
This is it.
It's Himmel's handwriting.
♪
[FERN] What does it say?
It's the tale
of a ridiculous journey.
Just everyday minutiae.
Here. I hope that you enjoy it.
At last, our fare
is paid in full.
I've heard plenty of stories
about the elven mage
who traveled
with the party of heroes,
but I never dreamed
I'd meet her.
So, what gave it away?
The wistful look
that came to your face
when you skimmed over the book.
I can tell that
it's important to you.
You should keep it.
There are plenty
of other valuable books
tucked away in here.
That's payment enough for me.
Did it actually
show on my face?
Only a little.
[SAILOR] Let's be off.
We'll reach the far shore
before sunset.
[FRIEREN] Mm...
A collection of catchphrases.
[sighs]
My! What a waste
of good pages.
Hang on, I wanna try!
"I hope you brought
your coin purse, beast.
For I, Stark the Warrior,
shall make you pay!"
[STARK] Uh...
[SAILOR] It's a kraken!
[STARK] There are
sea monsters in a lake?
[FRIEREN]
Your yelling provoked it.
You're kidding!
Think fast.
If we don't defeat it quickly,
we shall all meet
a watery grave.
-[FERN] Mistress Frieren!
-[STARK] Frieren!
They're weak to well-placed
welts with...
Hey! Huh?
So, slaying a serpent is
as simple as it seems, sonny.
I get it.
She's picked now
to test her spell
that allows you
to say tongue twisters
without tripping
over your words.
[STARK] Huh?
Our lives are on the line
and you two are worried
about tongue twisters?
Creepy.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[FRIEREN]
It's 3,000 - meter drop.
[FERN] Mistress,
it's reacting to our mana.
[HIMMEL] If we defeat
the Demon King,
a time will come when anyone
can enjoy this beautiful sight.